careerbuilder.co.in 2019-05-05

# CareerBuilder India - Privacy

These days, we all need to be smart about the way we use our own personal data. CareerBuilder India has always been on the forefront of privacy issues, and we're constantly refining our Privacy Policy to ensure that you can get your job done - all on your own terms and completely anonymously if you so desire. So that you can be smarter about the way you manage your career, CareerBuilder India continues to strive to provide the safest possible environment for you to search and apply to jobs. 

******CareerBuilder India Precautions**

**OVERVIEW**  
We have created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our commitment to protecting information you submit. This Privacy Policy only applies to data gathered on the CareerBuilder India web site (the "Site"), and does not apply to any other information or web site. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may update it from time to time. This Privacy Policy is effective as of February 1, 2005. Each time you visit the Site or provide us with information, you are, by doing so, accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy at that time. You agree that by using the Site you are expressly and affirmatively consenting to our use and disclosure of the information that you provide, and consenting to receive emails, as described below in this Privacy Policy. 

**PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
In order to operate the Site in an efficient and effective manner and provide users with information on job postings and services that may be of interest to them, CareerBuilder India may collect personal information, including contact information (such as an email address), from its users. In addition, this information allows us to provide users with private and secure areas to post and modify their original content on our site (e.g., jobs and CVs). We also automatically track certain information based upon your behavior on the Site and use this information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand, protect and serve users in general. This information may include the URL that a user has just come from (whether this URL is on our Site or not), the URL a user goes to next (whether this URL is on our Site or not), a user’s computer browser information, and their IP address. 

You agree that CareerBuilder India may use your personal information to contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests (such as relevant job postings and services), or provides administrative notices or communications applicable to your use of the Site. By accepting this Privacy Policy, you expressly agree to receive this information. If you do not wish to receive these communications, we encourage you to opt out of any further receipt by following the opt out provisions provided in each such communication. 

We do not sell our users' personal information to anyone for any reason if the user has indicated a desire for us to keep the information private. When posting jobs and CVs, our users decide for themselves how much contact information they wish to display (we enable private communication for those who choose to hide this information). 

All users should be aware, however, that when they voluntarily display or distribute personal information (such as their email address or CV), that information can be collected and used by others. This may result in unsolicited messages from third parties for which CareerBuilder India is not responsible. 

CareerBuilder India may also disclose specific user information when we determine that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, to cooperate with or seek assistance from law enforcement or to protect the interests or safety of CareerBuilder India or other users of the Site. In addition, personal information we have collected may be passed on to a third party in the event of a transfer of ownership or assets or a bankruptcy of CareerBuilder India. 

**ABOUT COOKIES**  
At CareerBuilder India, we use cookies only for the protection and convenience of our users. Cookies enable us to serve secure pages to our users without asking them to sign in repeatedly. If a user's system is idle for more than an hour, however, the cookie will expire, forcing the user to sign in again to continue their session. This prevents unauthorized access to the user's information while they are away from their computer. You may have the ability to reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent; however, some CareerBuilder India features or services may not function properly without cookies. 

Third-Party Cookies: In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. 

**ADVERTISING**  
We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information about you and your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services of interest to you. 

**WHAT YOU SHOULD KNOW**  
CareerBuilder India cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Therefore, although we are committed to protecting your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private. As a user of the Site, you understand and agree that you assume all responsibility and risk for your use of the Site, the internet generally, and the documents you post or access and for your conduct on and off the Site.

^  Back to top

| 

**Protect Yourself**

**SOME IMPORTANT TIPS TO USE WHEN DEALING WITH PROSPECTIVE EMPLOYERS**

| 

\- 

| 

Never give out your social security number to a prospective employer.   
  
---|---  
  
\- 

| 

Never provide credit card or bank numbers or monetary transaction of any sort.   
  
\- 

| 

Be cautious when dealing with contacts outside of your own country.   
  
\- 

| 

Do not provide any non-work related personal information (i.e. social security number, eye color, marital status etc.) over the phone or online.   
  
**OTHER PRIVACY FEATURES ON CAREERBUILDER INDIA**  
You never need to provide data to search for jobs  
Logging into CareerBuilder India is always an optional task for you to take, (although logging in does give you access to smarter job search tools such as my careerbuilder, Personal Search Agents and Saved Searches.) 

**YOU NEVER NEED TO PROVIDE DATA TO APPLY FOR A JOB ON CAREERBUILDER INDIA**  
When posting your CV, CareerBuilder India offers you three privacy options. Standard posting will give you the most visibility to the broadest employer audience possible - but because your confidentiality is as important to us as it is to you, we also offer Anonymous and Private posting options. 

**POST A CV**  
Posting your CV on CareerBuilder India puts you in front of thousands of employers with open positions each day. When you post your CV, we automatically create a registration for you using the email address and password that you supply. When you return to the site in the future you will use that same email address and password to access and edit your existing CV. 

**CV PRIVACY OPTIONS**  
We know that our job seekers have varying levels of comfort when it comes to posting their CV on the Internet. To accommodate the needs of all users, CareerBuilder India has 3 levels of privacy from which you can choose. 

**STANDARD POSTING**  
This option gives you the most visibility to the broadest employer audience possible by making your CV searchable in our CV Database. 

**ANONYMOUS POSTING**  
You can also post to the public CV database without any of your contact information being displayed. (If you use this option be sure to remove your contact information from the body of the CV.) The anonymous option also allows you to only display selected pieces of contact information. 

**PRIVATE POSTING FOR APPLY ONLINE ONLY**  
This option allows you to post your CV on CareerBuilder India without having it searched by employers. The benefit is that you can quickly and easily apply for jobs without retyping your information. 

**YOUR GENERAL CONTACT INFORMATION**  
Managing your privacy is as simple as selecting which pieces of your contact information are displayed. This is done in the section of the CV form called "Contact Information." Using option 3 above requires that you select the Apply Online Only option from the "Contact Information" section at the bottom of the edit form, as shown below.

^  Back to top  

**How to Spot Fraud **

**EMAIL AND ONLINE FRAUD**  
Unfortunately, email and online fraud are continuing concerns for virtually all businesses that operate on the Internet. Please be aware that, from time to time, fraudulent emails have been circulated to CareerBuilder India users that appear to be from  
CareerBuilder India but which are, in fact, sent by imposters. CareerBuilder India is not sending these fraudulent emails. If you receive an email or pop-up window requesting that you sign in to CareerBuilder India and provide your personal information, do not respond.

**HELP US MONITOR FRAUD**  
Please be advised that CareerBuilder India will never initiate a request for your personal information via email or pop-up window. If you ever receive a request for this type of sensitive information, please do not respond and immediately contact CareerBuilder India using our feedback form. 

^  Back to top
